hello everyone
and welcome to yet another ae2 tutorial
to get started, we need to connect our system to a power source
we can do that via an energy acceptor
which will bridge power from other mods
in GTNH, AE2 power consumption can be quite relevant
so I suggest placing the energy acceptor close to your generators
and possibly have some dedicated energy buffer for it
now that our system is powered
we can start giving it a purpose by adding some parts
we start with a drive
which will host up to 10 storage cells to have some inventory capacity
to access this inventory
we can expand our system with a terminal
but that's not the only way of interacting with this inventory
to passively move around items
we have import and export buses
but better yet, we have interfaces, which will keep set amounts of items in place
we also have storage buses
which will allow to directly interact with external storages
but we will see those better later on
the next thing we have to talk about is cables and channels
without a controller, we can only attach up to 8 parts to our system
adding one extra will cause it to collapse
to avoid this limitation
we need to sort out the communication between those parts with the help of a controller
every part we add to our network will require to be connected to our central controller
but cables can only carry a limited amount of connections
more precisely
32 for dense cables and 8 for normal cables
glass cable is the cheapest one
but it can't be painted
which could be a problem
since cable loops can cause unpredictable behaviors
finally we have smart cables
those are more expensive
but will allow you to see the amount of used channels without using any tool
to connect all of your base
you will probably have to reach far places
but long cables could become expensive
to cheap out we can use point to point connections
those things will bridge a cable across two points while using only one channel
meaning they can shrink channel usage by a factor of 32
to set up the P2P bridge
we have to use a memory card to link the input side to the output side
p2ps will however require a channel to work
so we set up a second network just for those
to power that extra network
we can draw some energy from our main network using a piece of quartz fiber
next, we can see how to make our system craft complex items on its own
to do that we start with a pattern terminal
where we can teach the system how to do each crafting step
for example, we can say that one iron dust can be turned into one iron ingot
we encode that recipe into a pattern
which we then move to an interface
that way when the system will need an iron ingot
it will move an iron dust to an inventory near that interface
and accept an iron ingot back
to make the process faster most of the time
you will want NEI to fill up your patterns
and your interfaces to be more compact and dedicated to a single machine
and when using gregtech single blocks
you have to remember to correctly set the machine inputs and outputs
with that I think I covered most of the basic stuff
now let's get into some more advanced stuff typical to GTNH
when dealing with multi blocks, if you don't have unlocked the CIBs
you'll have to split your solids and fluids into two different inventories
a cheap way of doing that is with ingredients buffers
but that solution will cause all sort of issues when scaling up
to fix the speed issues we can use a subnetwork
our interface will drop ingredients into the subnetwork interface
which can only store those inside the storage buses that are attached to the multi block
if you are working with a more expensive machine
and want it to work with different circuits
you can use paint to make sure that ingredients won't react with each other
if instead the issue is that the machine is too slow
you can use P2P interfaces to split the load
to do that, we simply upgrade the interface on our first machine
then like a P2P
we link it to a P2P interface on a second machine
that way we can split craftings across all of the machines we could want
to split the load even better and avoid recipe conflicts
we can add an advanced blocking card to the receiving interface
and turn on blocking mode on the main network one
that will ensure that no items will build up in the input bus
but it could also prevent parallel crafting
we can avoid this side effect by multiplying patterns
or allowing same recipe insertion
and now we can jump to some more complex stuff
assembly lines
as you know the main issue here is splitting all of the ingredients across all of the inputs
to do that you simply use ULV input buses
which can only hold one item stack
and then have decreasing priority on the crafting subnetworks buses
and nowadays this can be easily achieved with a new priority card
in this setup, enabling blocking mode with blocking cards is mandatory to avoid clogging
the only weak point of this setup is recipes that needed the same item in different spots
the mainstream way of fixing that issue is by creating some renamed copies of said item
which can be automated with a rename mold in a press
and now we can move on to more interesting stuff
such as the general purpose advance assembly line
to break it down
let's start by saying that those are 10 identical setups fed by point to point interfaces
so we should focus on just one of those lines
if we check one of those setups
we can see that each row is just an assembly line where each slice is fed whatever item is present in a dedicated subnetwork for this slice
I wanted to highlight that this is just a modular assembly line
where each slice is taking items from an external inventory, shared between all of the assembly lines in the same group
with that you should get that the only challenge is getting each item in a different subnetwork
to do that we create a set of sub networks that can only contain one item type
which can be easily achieved with digital singularity cells
then we place those networks in a way that resembles an assembly line
and feed the that setup the way we will feed an assembly line
to get a better view
here we have our main network interface
dropping into a distribution network interface
which will split ingredients into storage buses according to priority
also every interface must have blocking cards inside and blocking mode enabled
the next thing we should see is how to build a controller with a lot of usable channels
before we get started
I would like to tell you that this is not required
I have used about 100 controller faces to complete the stargate
and that can be easily achieved by basic layouts
with that I mean that this simple controller here is already providing as many channels as I used to build a star gate
and there is still plenty of unused space
anyways the way I built my controller is more or less like this
we start with a controller shell done like that
and then we add P2P all over the inner side
we add two wireless connectors to take out those P2P connection
and complete the controller cell like that
we take out each one of the wireless connector to an open space
where we build a wall for all of the P2P that will be bridged
connect all of the P2Ps of the controller with the P2Ps on the wall
finally, we add the easily accessible wireless connector that we will be using for our base
I didn't go much into the details
because I think I should first figure out a proper way of editing videos
and I think there are already plenty of good tutorials on YouTube on how to do those things
so I just try to showcase the most useful or interesting stuff
before I do anything else
I'd first want to know if I should go back to the text to speech or keep using my voice
but ideally
to ease editing and be closer to my preferred style
I would like to not have to type a script, and just improvise
but most importantly, I think that you should just test out whatever you want instead of blindly following a tutorial
and for that reason I will often reply "why" questions with "why not?" or "go and try yourself to find out"
I don't want to be mean
I just want to say that the best way of learning is by trial and error
for the next video
I will probably try to show answer to whatever questions I get in the comments
see you next time
bye bye
大家好
欢迎来到又一个 AE 教程
首先，我们需要给 AE 系统供电
我们可以通过能源接收器来做到这一点
它能将其他mod的电源转换为AE电
在GTNH中，给AE供电相当重要
所以我建议把能源接收器放在靠近发电机的地方
并且尽量放一些专门的能量缓存
现在我们的系统通电了
我们可以通过添加一些部分给它事干
我们从驱动器开始
它将容纳多达10个存储单元以具有库存容量
要访问此库存
我们可以用终端扩展我们的系统
但这并不是与库存交互的唯一方式
要被动地移动物品
我们有输入总线和输出总线
但更好的是，我们有ME接口，它将维持一定数量的物品
我们还有存储总线
这将允许与外部存储直接交互
但我们最好稍后再看它们
接下来我们要谈的是线缆和频道
如果没有控制器，我们最多只能将8个部件连接到AE上
再添加一个部件会导致系统崩溃
为了避免这种局限
我们需要在ME控制器的帮助下解决这些部分之间的通信
我们添加到网络中的每个部分都需要连接到中央控制器
但是线缆只能承载有限数量的连接
更准确地说
密集线缆能承载32个频道，普通线缆8个
玻璃线是最便宜的
但是无法被染色
这可能是个问题
因为线缆环路会导致不可预测的行为
最后是智能线缆
那玩意很贵
但可以让你在不使用任何工具的情况下查看使用的频道数量
要连接整个基地
你可能拉线缆到很远的地方
但长线缆可能会变得昂贵
为了省钱，我们可以使用p2p
这东西只用一个通道就能将两条线缆连接
这意味着他们可以将频道使用量减少32倍
要建立P2P连接
我们必须使用内存卡将输入端链接到输出端
然而，p2p需要一个通道才能工作
所以我们为此建立了第二个网络
为了给这个额外的网络供电
我们可以用一个石英纤维从主网络中汲取一些能量
接下来，我们可以看看如何让系统自己制作复杂的物品
为此，我们从样板终端开始
在那里我们可以教系统如何完成每个制作步骤
例如，我们可以说一个铁粉可以变成一个铁锭
我们将配方编码为样板
然后我们把它放到ME接口
这样当系统需要一个铁锭时
它会将铁粉移动到ME接口附近的库存中
并接受一个铁锭的返回
多数情况下，要让处理的速度更快
一般会用NEI写样板
并且让ME接口更加紧凑并专用于单台机器
在使用GT单方块机器时
你必须记住正确设置机器输入和输出
有了这个，我想我涵盖了大部分基本的东西
现在让我们进入一些GTNH特有的更高级的东西
在自动化多方块时，如果你没有解锁样板输入总成
你必须把物品和流体分别输入两个不同的仓室
一种便宜的方法是使用原材料缓存仓
但该解决方案在扩展时会导致各种问题
为了解决速度问题，我们可以使用子网
主网的ME接口会将材料送入子网的ME接口
子网的ME接口只能将那些材料存储在
贴着多方块机器的仓室的存储总线内
如果你使用的是更昂贵的机器
并希望它能同时使用不同的编程电路
你可以给仓室染色以确保不会串配方
如果问题是机器太慢了
你可以使用P2P接口来分配负载
为此，我们只需把一台机器上的ME接口升级成p2p的
然后像P2P一样
我们将其连接到第二台机器上的P2P接口
这样我们就可以把合成均摊到我们想要的所有机器
为了更好地分配负载并避免配方冲突
我们可以在接收端的ME接口中添加高级阻挡卡
并在主网的ME接口里打开阻挡模式
这将确保输入总线中不会堆积任何物品
但它也会限制机器并行
我们可以通过倍增样板来避免这个副作用
或允许输入相同的配方
现在我们可以跳到一些更复杂的东西
也就是——装配线
如你所知，这里的主要问题是在所有输入中均分材料
为此，你只需使用ULV输入总线
它只能容纳一组的物品
然后在子网的存储总线上逐渐降低优先级
如今，这操作可以通过优先卡轻松实现
在这套自动化中，必须使用阻挡卡
并启用阻挡模式，以避免原料堆积
这个设置的唯一弱点是
在不同的地方需要相同物品的配方
解决这个问题的主流方法是创建
所述物品的一些重命名副本
重命名可以通过压模机中的重命名模具实现自动化
现在我们可以继续更有趣的事情了
比如通用高级装配线
要拆开、揉碎了讲
首先，这是由p2p接口提供的10个相同的设置
所以我们应该只关注其中一条装配线
如果我们检查其中一个设置
我们可以看到，这就是个常规的装配线
其中每一层都在被动抽取该层的专用子网中存在的东西
我想强调的是，这就是一条模块化的装配线
其中每一层从外部库存中取出物品
这个库存是在同组的所有装配线之间共享的
这样说完，你应该明白唯一的挑战是
将每个物品放在不同的子网中
为此，我们创建了一系列只能包含一种物品的子网
这可以通过数字奇点元件轻松实现
然后我们将这些网络以类似于装配线的方式放置
并按照之前自动化装配线的方式给该设置输入物品
为了看得更清楚
这是我们的主网ME接口
输入物品到用于分配原料的子网的ME接口
子网ME接口会根据优先级将原料输入存储总线
存储总线对着的ME接口内部
都必须有阻挡卡并启用阻挡模式
接下来我们看看如何构建一个
具有大量可用频道的ME控制器
在我们开始之前
我想告诉你这不是必须的
我用了大约100个ME控制器的面来完成星门
这可以通过基本布局轻松实现
我的意思是这个简单的控制器已经提供了
和我用来建造星门一样多的频道
而且还有大量未使用的空间
无论如何，我构建控制器的方式大概是这样的：
我们从这样的控制器外壳开始
然后在内侧添加P2P
添加两个无线连接器来引出那些P2P通道
并像那样完成控制器单元
我们将无线连接器连到到一个开放空间
为所有被桥接的P2P建立一堵墙
将控制器的所有P2P与墙上的P2P连接起来
最后，我们添加易于访问的无线连接器
我们用它们联通整个基地
我没说太多细节
因为我想我做得合适视频剪辑
我认为YouTube上已经有很多关于AE的好教程
所以我只是想展示最有用或最有趣的东西
在我做其他事情之前
我首先想知道我是应该回到ai配音还是继续使用我的声音
但理想情况下
为了简化剪辑并更接近我喜欢的风格
我希望不写剧本，就即兴发挥
但最重要的是，我认为对于任何你想做的事情
应该先去试一试，而不是盲目地跟教程走
出于这个原因，我经常会用"为什么不呢"
或者"去试试看"来回答"为什么"的问题
我没有任何贬低的意思
我只想说最好的学习方法是通过试验和排除错误
对于下一个视频
我可能会试着回答评论区中的问题
下次见
拜拜
（一个部件占用一个频道）
(它能同时存储物品和流体）
（一个面能提供32个频道）
（现在他决定给速通类的视频三个音轨
口播英语、口播意大利、ai英语
其他类型的视频应该就只有口播英语）
（他之后并没有做这个）